<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Caroline Lamar</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Caroline Lamar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Python and R can talk to each other</title>
      <link>/post/2020/12/10/blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/12/10/blog-post/</guid>
      <description>Python and R can be thought of as two different languages of coding. There are certain packages such as reticulate, that can use interacting information from both R and Python. Reticulate allows you to run a Python session embedded in your R markdown, you can access code chunks created within R in Python and vice versa, and you can translate between R and Python objects when using things such Pandas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Inpatient Psychiatric Care by State - Caroline Lamar</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>The two datasets that I have chosen are from the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services and are active datasets that were last updated June 20, 2020. One dataset describes psychiatric care by state and the other by facility which contains facilities from all over the nation. There are some categorical variables describing the location of facilities. The numeric variables are Hours of Physical Restraint, Hours of Seclusion, Patients Discharged on Multiple Antipsychotic Medications, Patients Readmitted to Any Hospital 30 Days After Discharge, Patients Offered Alcohol and Drug Treatment and Patients Offered Tobacco Treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of Psychiatric Facilities Nationwide</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>library(tidyverse) library(ggplot2) ipfacility &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;quot;inpatientfacility.csv&amp;quot;) This dataset is from the U.S. Department of Health &amp;amp; Human Services updated through October 29, 2020. There are 1,597 different facilities with 14 different variables. There are some descriptor variables such as Facility ID, Name, Address, City, State, Location, Zip.Code, etc. The numeric variables are hrs.of.phys.res (the total hours of physical restraint from the facility),total hours of seclusion for each facility (hrs.of.seclusion), the number of patients discharged from each facility on multiple antipsychotic medications (pts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
